Guide to the Nils John Nilsson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Nils John Nilsson papers
1977-2009
SC0944
Nilsson, Nils J., 1933-
21 Linear feet and 4618.24 megabytes
Collection pertains to Nilsson's research and teaching and includes correspondence, notes and text for talks, papers, published articles, conference and meeting materials, and AV materials on artificial intelligence.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Nils John Nilsson
Nils J. Nilsson, Kumagai Professor of Engineering (Emeritus) in the Department of Computer Science at Stanford University, received his PhD degree in Electrical Engineering from Stanford in 1958. He spent twenty-three years at the Artificial Intelligence Center of SRI International working on statistical and neural-network approaches to pattern recognition, co-inventing the A* heuristic search algorithm and the STRIPS automatic planning system, directing work on the integrated mobile robot, SHAKEY, and collaborating in the development of the PROSPECTOR expert system. He has published five textbooks on artificial intelligence.
Professor Nilsson returned to Stanford in 1985 as the Chairman of the Department of Computer Science, a position he held until August 1990. Besides teaching courses on artificial intelligence and on machine learning, he has conducted research on flexible robots that are able to react to dynamic worlds, plan courses of action, and learn from experience. Professor Nilsson served on the editorial boards of the journal Artificial Intelligence and of the Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research. He was an Area Editor for the Journal of the Association for Computing Machinery. He is a past-president and Fellow of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence and is also a Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. He was a co-founder of Morgan Kaufmann Publishers, Inc.
Professor Nilsson is a foreign member of the Royal Swedish Academy of Engineering Sciences. He is a recipient of the IEEE "Neural-Network Pioneer" award, the IJCAI "Research Excellence" award, and the AAAI "Distinguished Service" award.
From Nilsson's home page at: http://ai.stanford.edu/~nilsson/
Scope and Contents note
Collection pertains to Nilsson's research and teaching and includes correspondence, notes and text for talks, papers, published articles, conference and meeting materials, and AV materials on artificial intelligence.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Computer Science Department. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Artificial intelligence.; Robotics.
Collection Contents
- Email and contacts [computer files], Series 1
  - E-mail, 1977-2001, 2003-2007; 110,276 computer files (TXT)
    Prof. Nilsson mentioned that the 2002 mail got lost somehow as he was changing computers.
  - China, 1981; 1 computer file(s) (TXT)
    The folder contains names and addresses of people Nils Nilsson met during his 1981 trip to China.
- Research [computer files], 1977-2007; Series 2
  - Actnet, 1990; 80 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to the precursor to the teleo‐reactive programming formalism.
  - Guggenheim application, 1990; 5 computer file(s)
    The folder contains of research grant application to John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation.
  - Location of Files Archived at SRI, 1985; 1 computer file(s) (TXT)
    The folder contains a list of the SRI tapes on which Nils' various SRI files were stored. The tapes may no longer be available at SRI.
  - Logic and AI papers and talks, 1987-1990; 20 computer file(s)
    The folder contains files relating to the use of logic in AI.
  - Miscellaneous Essays, 20 computer file(s)
  - Principia-ICA Project, 1987-1989; 24 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to the Principia-ICA project.
  - Proposals, 1988-1994; 148 computer file(s)
    The folder contains research proposals.
  - Reports, 1988-1995; 58 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to project reports.
  - Research Budgets, 1990-1995; 22 computer file(s)
  - Publications and their backup materials, 2004-2007; 35 computer file(s)
  - SRI Files, 1977-1989; 607 computer file(s)
    The folder contains files related to works at SRI (1961-1984). They are organized by year--each is a bit of hodge-podge and contains material related to papers, correspondence, reports, proposals, etc.
  - Teleo-Reactive Research, 1991-1999; 546 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to Nils' teleo-reactive programming formalism.
- Stanford administration [computer files], 1985-2006; Series 3
  - Computer Science Departmental Matters, 1985-1990; 295 computer file(s)
    The folder contains mostly material from Nils' days of being the chair of the Computer Science Dept. (1985-1990).
  - Computer Forum, 1990-1996; 177 computer file(s)
    Contains materials related to the department's industrial affiliates program.
  - Computer Science Department Timeline, 2006; 6 computer file(s) (PDF)
  - Computer Science Department Proposals, 1985-1989; 4 computer file(s) (TXT)
    The folder contains proposals to AT&T.
  - Official correspondence, 1995; 2 computer file(s) (TXT)
  - Photos of Robots, 2 computer file(s) (TIFF)
  - University Committees, 1987-1990; 6 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to university committees on which Nils served.
- Stanford teaching [computer files], 1987-2005; Series 4
  - AI Qualifying Examinations, 1987-1989; 6 computer file(s)
    The folder contains questions Nils and others asked Stanford AI PhD candidates during their "qualifying exams."
  - Computer Science Department Comprehensive Exams, 1991-1993; 38 computer file(s)
  - Courses and Students, 1984-2000; 3451 computer file(s)
    The folder contains files related to courses Nils taught and some student information.
  - Curis Projects, 2002, 2005; 81 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to the Curis projects which are summer computer science projects undertaken by undergraduates. Nils participated for a couple of summers.
- Books and comments [computer files], 1980-2009; Series 5
  - Guggenheim application 2007, 6 computer file(s) (PDF)
    The folder contains application of book writing grant to the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation.
  - Books, 1980-2009; 3284 computer file(s)
    The folder contains files of some of Nils' books.
  - Santa Fe Institute, 1991-1993; 61 computer file(s)
    The folder contains materials related to Nils' visits to the Santa Fe Institute.
  - Reviews and comments about papers and books, 1993-2005; 12 computer file(s)
    The folder contains Nils' reviews and comments about papers and books.
- Professional organizations and services [computer files], 1981-2009; Series 6
  - AAAI 2005 Distinguished Service award Photos, 13 computer file(s) (JPG)
  - Awards and Ceremonies, 1989-1995; 8 computer file(s)
  - Interview, 2006; 1 computer file(s) (MP4)
  - Interviews Luminaries, 2007; 11 computer file(s) (PDF)
    The folder contains interviews of John McCarthy and Edward Feigenbaum by Nils.
  - Photos of Nils Nilsson
  - Presentations, Workshops and Conferences, 1981-2006; 1878 computer file(s)
- Events files, Series 7
  correspondence, programs, abstracts, papers, etc.
  - Navy R&D Clinic, September 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Syllabi: CS 382 Winter 1969; EE 298 [UCLA] Spring 1964; EE 353 Summer 1962; CS 225 Spring 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - IJCAI [International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence] 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IJCAI 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1970-71 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Computer Models of Learning and Adaptive Behavior: grant application and proposal for research, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scotland Problem-Solving Session, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACM Spring Conference 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MI-7 [Seventh International Machine Intelligence Workshop] 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cal Tech Robot Seminar 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1972 Robot talks, strips [overhead slides] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - FJCC [Fall Joint Computer Conference] 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pajaro Dunes problem solving workshop 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Wash.-N.Y. March 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Robot equipment workshop 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence originated by IJCAI-73, 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - IJCAI 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Forms, etc, for IJCAI 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - IJCAI 1973 miscellaneous letters (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - SRI-Washington briefing [seminar on computer-based consultants] 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - IFIP Congress 1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - May trip to Washington DC, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - July trip to Washington DC, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Pantell [Prof. R. H. Pantell] seminar 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous talks, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - University talks, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cal Tech meeting 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - February trip, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - April trip, Washington DC, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - ARPA / PI meeting 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Licklides visit April 23, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - July Washington trip 1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - December trip to Washington DC 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Military application of AI conference 1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Trip to Bakersfield (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - September trip to Washington 1976 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - AIM [Artificial Intelligence in Medicine] workshop 1976 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - NCC [National Computer Conference] 1976 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Syllabus: CS 225, Fall 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - West Texas State University trip 1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Psychology Conference 1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - IBM talk March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Trip March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Jim Adams P.S. seminar May 1977 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Hawaii [Workshop on Pattern-directed Inference Systems] May 1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Wegner conference [Research Directions in Software Technology] 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - IJCAI 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [Automatic] Deduction Conference 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Leningrad trip report 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MI-9, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - USSR April 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - MIT trip 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brown [University] talk 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - France trip 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cornell talk, December 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Framework for AI Seminar at UMass (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Amherst trip [teaching at UMass Fall] 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - HOUND [Heuristically-Oriented, Unprogrammed New Deducer] talk April 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Univ. of Maryland August 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - IFIP 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - May 1978 trip (ONR, ARPA, WPAFB, NASA) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - AIM 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CMU [Carnegie Mellon Univ.] trip January 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Annual Review 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Apple Visit 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - CSD Reunion [Computer Science at Stanford] 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - IJCAI 87 / Proposed Locations (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - MIT distinguished lecture May 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - MIT – Foundations of AI – June 1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - ICA NASA proposals 1987-89 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Foundations of AI Conference 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - AAAI July 1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - University of Washington January 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - University of Washington, Dept. of Computer Science Self-Study Nov. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - University of Washington, Dept. of Electrical Engineering Self-Study Oct. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - DARPA 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - TI [Texas Instruments] visit December 1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - FCCSET November 1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NASA Workshop November 1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Asilomar Conference November 1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - DARPA planning meeting Nov. 1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Planning Workshop [Rochester, NY] 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Rochester Planning Workshop October 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Glenwood Meeting November 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NRC (National Research Council) CS Study April 1988 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - September 1988 Frosh debate [new student orientation event] (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - UC Santa Cruz talk May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - AAAI Committee on Strategic Directions (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Conference on Gifted and Talented April 1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - DARPA Advisory Committee (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - School of Earth Science Industrial Associates Seminar Day 1988 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Neural Nets [overhead project slides] 1988 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - AAAI 1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Tektronix trip July 1988 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Snowbird Conference July 1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - ICA Review [overhead project slides] May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - ICA talk 1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Black Student Advanced Degree Program discussion Oct. 1988 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Schwartz Visit, February 1988 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Nilsson's New Years Day party 1989 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - CYC workshop January 1989 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - UCSD April 1989 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - AAAI Symposium Spring 1989 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Retreat Agenda responses [Computer Science Dept. faculty retreat] May 1989 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Washington DC trip June 1989 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - NASA Day June 21, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - IJCAI 1989 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - AAAI talk March 1989 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - 1989 Visiting Committee [SU Computer Science] (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - ML 91 [Eighth International Workshop on Machine Learning] June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - ICGA-91 conference schedule; Genetic Algorithms July 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Santa Fe, Learning in Economics, Psychology and Computer Science, January 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Kumagai dinner March 18, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Boston/Cambridge talks, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AAAI July 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AI Day on Campus ACTNET June 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CIS talk [Paradigm Shifts in AI] April 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Forum talk slides overhead type] 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Israeli AI Conference Dec.1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - First Foresight Conference on Nanotechnology 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Barry Boehm visit, November 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - CS Dept. 25th Anniversary 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - AAAI-91 Program July 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Santa Fe, Adaptive Computation, August 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - JMC Symposium [in honor of John McCarthy] Sept. 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Workshop on Computational Learning, Berkeley, Sept. 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Rockwell, January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Computer Form [24th Annual Meeting] Feb. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Santa Fe, March 1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - AIPS Conference, June 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - SFI [Santa Fe Institute]/Stanford Symposium July 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - AAAI August 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Rutgers Computer Science Review Oct. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - SFI Approaches to AI, Nov. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - IAS-3 conference, Pittsburgh, Feb. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Stanford Computer Form [25th Annual Meeting] Feb. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - SFI Reinforcement Learning in Robotics Workshop March 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Florida, Human & Machine Cognition [workshop] May 1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - NSF Grant 1992-94 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - NSF. Autonomous Agents [research] 1994-99 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - SFI. Bottom-up Robotics May 1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - ML [Machine Learning] Conference June 1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - AAAI July 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - AAAI Fall Symposium 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Washington DC Trip October 1993 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Adaptive Computation, Ann Arbor, Nov. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - AAAI Spring Symposium 1994 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Comp. Science Dept. retreat 1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - AAAI Fall Workshop, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Caracas [Iberoamerican Congress on AI] 1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - ISI trip March 1995 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Univ. of Washington May 1995 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - SFI, Biological and Computational Landscapes, July 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Machine Learning conference 1995 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Shakey – SRI – November 1995 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Neural networks conference, Australia, Nov. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - AAAI, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - NRC – AI history Feb. 28, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Smithsonian 1997 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - AAAI, Madison, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Hebrew University committee, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - SFI, Embodied-Motor Knowledge, March 1999 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - AAAI, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - York (University of) trip 2001 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - IJCAI 2001 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Big Picture" AI workshop March 2004 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Festschrift for Edward A. Feigenbaum, March 2006 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - AAAI 2005 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - 40 Years of Computer Science at Stanford: A Symposium and Celebration, March 21, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Model-Directed Macro Expansion [overhead slides] ca. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Carnegie I [talks – A Framework for AI] 1978 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - COMTEC – Rome Air Development Center – March 1979 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Rutgers: Proceedings of the First A.I.M. Workshop 1975 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - AI Project – ideas 1980s (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - COMTEC 2000, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - ONR San Diego meeting, April 1979 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Washington DC trip Jan. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Texas [Automated] Deduction workshop 1979 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - RADC, January 1979 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - DENDRAL / NIH Site Visit (Stanford) Dec. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Rand [Team Performance] Nov. workshop 1979 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Cognitive Science [conference] San Diego August 1979 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Hayward State talk May 1979 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - COMTEC, McLean, Virginia, Feb. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - IBM talk, March 1979 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - [Saul] Amarel site visit 1980 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - RADC April 1980 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - AI and Philosophy conference March 1980 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - McKemie / Denicoff January 1980 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - DOE, NSF, ARPA January 1980 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Formal Methods [in AI] August 1980 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - RADC meeting August 1980 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - IBM – SHARE presentation March 1980 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - DAI [Distributed Artificial Intelligence] workshop June 1980 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - ARPA, RADC trip Sept. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - LISP conference 1980 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Rand Role-Based Systems August 1980 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - AAAI August 1980 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - AIM August 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - JPL Trip November 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ONR October 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Trip to NSA, NSF, ONR October 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - RADC Symposium September 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Washington D.C. Trip Druffel November 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Addresses Japan & Misc. July 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - China Trip October 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - CMU Dist. Lecture April 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - CMU Visiting Comm. March 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Washington D.C. Visit February 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - SOC Visit January 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ohlander August 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carl Vinson Trip July 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Applied Materials Visit July 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Akzona Corp. June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - June Trip to Washington D.C. June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - AIC Retreat February 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - AAAI August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - San Diego NOSC Trip June 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Japan/China September 1981 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - IJCAI Talk August 1891 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - IJCAI August 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - ARPA LISP Meeting, Kahn Visit/Wash. Trip April 1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - AIC Christmas Alumni Party December 1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - AIC Retreat – Monterey Dunes November 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - MI – 10 [Machine Intelligence Research Unit] November 1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Sweden December 1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - AΩ November 1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - AIC Retreat November 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - November Trips WDC November 1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - AAAI August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - SIR Talk March 1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - WDC Trip June 1982 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - WDC March 1982 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - WDC Trips January 1982 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Town Hall February 1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - ATP Prize 1982 January 1983 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Prize September 1982 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - NSF January 1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - IJCAI Panel Paper August 1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - UMINN Talk May 1983 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - UMICU of AAAS May 1983 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - CSD Retreat May 1983 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - ARPA PI Meeting April 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Sweden Trips March 1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Air Force Academy March 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Fernbach Committee August 1983 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - AAAI – Pres September 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - AAAI August 1983 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - IJCAI August 1983 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Research Symposium to Honor Marvin Denicoff December 1983 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Autonomous Vehicle Conference October 1983 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Austria Meeting August 1983 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - AIC Day October 17, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Viewgraphs/Prolog ~1980? (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - R. Kahn Meeting November 1983 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - AIC Leaders Retreat December 1983 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Annual Reviews NY March 1984 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Interview with Nils Nilsson Whole Earth… January 1984 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - DARPA Meeting June 1984 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Trips to Washington D.C. August 1984 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - AAIC August 1984 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Triangle Tables (Viewgraphs) July 1984 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Workshop on Non-Monotonic Reasoning October 1984 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Quintus November 1984 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - OTA Workshop on AI November 1984 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Annual Review of AI October 1983 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Publications, Series 8
  - 1962-1972 (1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1962-1972 (2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1962-1972 (3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1962-1972 (4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Drafts & Memos 1965-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Drafts & Appendices 1960's (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Drafts & Appendices 1960's (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1959-1973 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1959-1973 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Speeches & Interviews (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Drafts 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1958-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1973-1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Drafts 1978-1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - AI Science Research Council (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - An Application of the Theory of Games to Radar Reception Problems, Stanford Ph.D. thesis 1958 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence 1961-October 1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence January 1964-February 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence March-December 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence January 1966-March 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence May-December 1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)